Summary

In my 10+ years in public service I have focused on software and application development. More recently, I've played major roles in project management attaining my Project Management Professional® and Certified ScrumMaster® certification and a Navy Superior Civilian Service award. I'm currently enrolled in an Executive Potential Program, a competency-based leadership development program focused on leading change.

Work Experience

Defense Media Activity

IT Specialist - Navy Chief of Web

07/2017 - Present

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Led cross functional teams of designers, developers, QA specialists to modernize Navy websites and mobile
 apps to allow the members of the Navy public affairs community to easily create and distribute content across
 the Navy enterprise.
- Received Navy Superior Civilian Service award for a "historic transformation of the Navy's flagship digital presence marking it's first significant modernization in 20 years"

EXAMPLES

Navy Flagship website
Navy All Hands website

The Official US Navy App: IOS
The Official US Navy App: Android (January 2022)

Selective Service System

IT Specialist - Project Manager / Developer

12/2015 - 07/2017

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

• Led team of developers and database administrators in a business process improvement effort improving the system that rapidly provides personnel into the armed forces in the event of a national emergency

TASKS

- Developed and managed SSS mission-critical project articulating areas improvement and bringing project development expertise in-house
- Directed 508 compliance initiative focusing on video portions of public website ensuring people with disabilities have access to electronic and information technology

Internal Revenue Service

IT Specialist - Project Manager / Developer

01/2011 - 12/2015

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

• Led development team building desktop applications to collect and compute statistical data that informs other government agencies and the public how the tax system works

Matthew Bogdan Resume | mbog83@hotmail.com | Page 1

TASKS

- Produced electronic correspondence tracking system to take place of time consuming paper signing process resulting in Special Act Award
- Led team of programmers to convert program from Oracle Forms to Visual Studio NET in a Project Manager role increasing security measures and coding efficiencies
- Played lead role in cross-divisional team to build agency framework & templates to improve efficiency of developer programming

Holabird Sports

Web / Graphics Designer 03/2007 - 05/2011

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Increased brand/product awareness through traditional print and digital web advertising

TASKS

- Assisted with web redesign through analysis of user experience tests increasing conversion rates in purchasing process
- Increased brand/product awareness through traditional and digital advertising using Adobe Photoshop/Illustrator
- Promoted sales with technical product descriptions using creative writing skills

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Master's degree Computer and Information Sciences and Support Services 2022-

Towson University

Bachelor's Computer Information Systems 2010 - 2011

The Community College of Baltimore County

Interactive Design Certificate Computer Graphics and Visual Communication 2004 – 2007

Volunteer

Assistant coach of youth soccer, baseball and basketball